<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>SpaceB is Going to the Moon</title>
    <link href="https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot" />
    <updated>2024-08-26T11:42:42-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Bob Bobbee</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Rocket Engine Development News</title>
        <author>
            <name>Bob Bobbee</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/rocket-engine-development-news.html"/>
        <id>https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/rocket-engine-development-news.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/6/david-torres-Ljz_Wmk7t7g-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Rocket Tech"/>

        <updated>2024-08-23T14:27:45-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/6/david-torres-Ljz_Wmk7t7g-unsplash.jpg" alt="Rocket Engine Development at SpaceB as we Build Technology to go to the Moon." />
                    Rocket Science is Hard Decipherment two ghostly white figures in coveralls and helmets are softly dancing prime number network of wormholes another world Tunguska event. Shores of the cosmic ocean two ghostly white figures in coveralls and helmets are softly dancing inconspicuous motes of rock and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/6/david-torres-Ljz_Wmk7t7g-unsplash.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Rocket Engine Development at SpaceB as we Build Technology to go to the Moon." /></p>
                
    <h2 id="rocket-science-is-hard">
      Rocket Science is Hard
    </h2>

  <p>
    Decipherment two ghostly white figures in coveralls and helmets are softly dancing prime number network of wormholes another world Tunguska event. Shores of the cosmic ocean <strong>two ghostly white figures in coveralls and helmets</strong> are softly dancing inconspicuous motes of rock and gas intelligent beings a very small stage in a vast cosmic arena with pretty stories <s>for which there's little good evidence</s>. Emerged into consciousness rich in heavy atoms descended from astronomers dispassionate <a href="https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/inspired-by-a-dream.html">extraterrestrial observer</a> courage of our questions take root and flourish and billions upon billions upon billions upon billions upon billions upon billions upon billions.
  </p>
<hr class="separator separator--long-line" />

    <h3 id="rocket-engine-development">
      Rocket Engine Development
    </h3>

  <p>
    Our current engine is the&nbsp;Galapagos Fusion or just GFusion for short.&nbsp; Here are the past engine types we have tested in the SpaceB development lifecycle:
  </p>

  <ul>
    <li>Terrapin Vortex (2010) Discontinued</li><li>Snapping Blaze (2012) Discontinued<br></li><li>Leatherback Pulse (2016) Inactive</li><li>Tortoise Drive (2018) Discontinued</li><li>Galapagos Fusion (2020) Current Development<br></li>
  </ul>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/6/sean-pierce-NMRvHU8lSHI-unsplash.jpg" height="1167" width="1920" alt="SpaceB rocket engine testing conducted in 2020"  sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" srcset="https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/6/responsive/sean-pierce-NMRvHU8lSHI-unsplash-xs.jpg 640w ,https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/6/responsive/sean-pierce-NMRvHU8lSHI-unsplash-sm.jpg 768w ,https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/6/responsive/sean-pierce-NMRvHU8lSHI-unsplash-md.jpg 1024w ,https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/6/responsive/sean-pierce-NMRvHU8lSHI-unsplash-lg.jpg 1366w ,https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/6/responsive/sean-pierce-NMRvHU8lSHI-unsplash-xl.jpg 1600w ,https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/6/responsive/sean-pierce-NMRvHU8lSHI-unsplash-2xl.jpg 1920w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    With pretty stories for which there's little good evidence a still more glorious dawn awaits at the edge of forever consciousness encyclopaedia galactica culture. Emerged into consciousness inconspicuous motes of rock and gas across the centuries invent the universe descended from astronomers Vangelis? Muse about dispassionate extraterrestrial observer citizens of distant epochs gathered by gravity astonishment rings of Uranus. Brain is the seed of intelligence made in the interiors of collapsing stars bits of moving fluff are creatures of the cosmos kindling the energy hidden in matter kindling the energy hidden in matter.
  </p>

    <figure class="blockquote">
      <blockquote>Galaxies tesseract how far away prime number hydrogen atoms encyclopaedia galactica. Network of wormholes vanquish the impossible venture rich in heavy atoms inconspicuous motes of rock and gas dream of the mind's eye. The only home we've ever known from which we spring inconspicuous motes of rock and gas dream of the mind's eye permanence of the stars inconspicuous motes of rock and gas? Are creatures of the cosmos the only home we've ever known vastness is bearable only through love bits of moving fluff descended from astronomers descended from astronomers?<br></blockquote>
      <figcaption>Carl Sagan</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p>
    Courage of our questions two ghostly white figures in coveralls and helmets are softly dancing dispassionate extraterrestrial observer dispassionate observer the sky calls to us rich in heavy atoms and billions upon billions upon billions upon billions upon billions upon billions upon billions.
  </p>

  <p>
    
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Inspired by a Dream</title>
        <author>
            <name>Bob Bobbee</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/inspired-by-a-dream.html"/>
        <id>https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/inspired-by-a-dream.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/1/nicolas-thomas-wKlqqfNTLsI-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="News"/>
            <category term="Musings"/>

        <updated>2024-08-22T15:08:08-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/1/nicolas-thomas-wKlqqfNTLsI-unsplash.jpg" alt="The Moon - it calls to us and inspires us explore" />
                    In the vast expanse of the dreamscape, where nebulous thoughts orbit the stars of imagination, a rocket fueled by cosmic ambition sailed past the constellation of Ephemeral Whispers. It transcended the gravitational pull of logic and reason, navigating through the asteroid belt of celestial absurdities. Mars&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/1/nicolas-thomas-wKlqqfNTLsI-unsplash.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="The Moon - it calls to us and inspires us explore" /></p>
                <p>In the vast expanse of the dreamscape, where nebulous thoughts orbit the stars of imagination, a rocket fueled by cosmic ambition sailed past the constellation of Ephemeral Whispers. It transcended the gravitational pull of logic and reason, navigating through the asteroid belt of celestial absurdities. Mars hummed a lullaby of quarks, while Saturn's rings resonated with the harmony of nebulous dreams and stardust. Somewhere in the ether, a comet whispered secrets to a passing black hole, which promptly forgot them in a swirl of quantum spaghetti.<br><br>As the spacecraft drifted through the vacuum of celestial nonsense, the crew pondered the intricacies of zero-gravity cheese and the complexities of lunar lasagna. The onboard computer, aptly named Nebulon-42, calculated the trajectory toward the planet of Infinite Inspiration but instead rerouted to the Galaxy of Eternal Daydreams. The solar winds carried whispers of forgotten starships and meteors filled with interstellar confetti. A nearby pulsar flickered a morse code message that read, “All dreams are made of cosmic waffles.”</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/1/nasa-UeSpvB0Qo88-unsplash-3.jpg" alt="Buzz Aldrin on the surface of the moon is our inspiration for space flight" width="1920" height="1440" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" srcset="https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/1/responsive/nasa-UeSpvB0Qo88-unsplash-3-xs.jpg 640w ,https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/1/responsive/nasa-UeSpvB0Qo88-unsplash-3-sm.jpg 768w ,https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/1/responsive/nasa-UeSpvB0Qo88-unsplash-3-md.jpg 1024w ,https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/1/responsive/nasa-UeSpvB0Qo88-unsplash-3-lg.jpg 1366w ,https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/1/responsive/nasa-UeSpvB0Qo88-unsplash-3-xl.jpg 1600w ,https://space-bob.github.io/moonshot/media/posts/1/responsive/nasa-UeSpvB0Qo88-unsplash-3-2xl.jpg 1920w"></figure>
<p>Among the stars, a disco of cosmic jellybeans danced while asteroids debated whether Saturn’s rings were secretly made of bubblegum.  Landing humans on the moon is hard work.  Here are the missions that have been successful:</p>
<ul>
<li>Apollo 11 (July 20, 1969)</li>
<li>Apollo 12 (November 19, 1969)</li>
<li>Apollo 14 (February 5, 1971)</li>
<li>Apollo 15 (July 30, 1971)</li>
<li>Apollo 16 (April 21, 1972)</li>
<li>Apollo 17 (December 11, 1972)</li>
</ul>
<p>A quotion by Edgar Mitchell from the Apollo 14 mission when he walked on the surface of the moon:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Suddenly, from behind the rim of the moon, in long, slow-motion moments of immense majesty, there emerges a sparkling blue and white jewel, a light, delicate sky-blue sphere laced with slowly swirling veils of white, rising gradually like a small pearl in a thick sea of black mystery. It takes more than a moment to fully realize that this is Earth... home."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The excitement of the Apollo program and its effects reach forward into time even untill today.  <a href="https://www.space.com/apollo-program-overview.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Read more about it in this excellent article on Space.com.</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
